Good morning. You're watching the
program with Ted R and John Kuryaku.
It's Thursday, November 20th, 2025.
Thank you for joining us and good
morning, John.
>> Good morning, Ted. How you doing?
>> I'm doing good. A little cold where I
am, but that's what it's supposed to be
in mid mid to late November. Um, so, uh,
yeah, you know, I always look for CIA
related news for us for obvious reasons.
And, uh, today there was, uh, more than
usual. There was more than usual
yesterday. I don't know, there's
something in the air. Um, so, uh, lots
going on. Uh, I know you may have a few
mild opinions about Ambassador Mike
Cuckabe's meeting with the, uh, freaking
[clears throat]
>> proud American patriot Jonathan Bard.
Um, that's a crazy story.
>> Huckabe should be fired right now. Right
now.
>> We will talk about that obviously. Um,
you know, uh, whenever I see CIA cover
up in JFK assassination, I always think
conspiracy [__]
>> Yeah.
>> Today though, this is a mainstream
story. This is in Politico. It's in
Axios. Former CIA historian is stepping
forward as a whistleblower. It's really
interesting. Um, so about what you know,
basically there's still stuff coming out
from this thing that happened, you know,
basically a couple of months after I was
born and I was born in 1963.
Um, so we'll get into that. Uh, Donald
Trump is meeting with his new bestie,
Zoron Mandani, tomorrow.
>> I know it's crazy. at the Oval Office
and you know whatever else y'all want to
talk about uh in the Rumble and YouTube
live chats. If you're watching live, you
can go ahead and type that in and uh we
uh producer Robbie West will
uh post it up to us and uh we will
answer your questions as much as we can.
We are here Monday through Friday 9:00
a.m. Eastern time. Uh and so uh please
like, follow, and share the show. We
really need and uh des and really appro
and uh really appreciate your generous
support uh in all respects for the show
including but not exclusively
financially. Um and so John, what would
you like to I have a feeling you might
like to talk about ambassador Huckabe.
>> I feel like exploding about Huckabe. So,
it turns out that last July,
Ambassador to Israel, U, former governor
of Arkansas, Mike Huckabe, and the
deputy chief of mission, [snorts]
uh, met with convicted spy Jonathan
Pard. Now, Jonathan Pard was convicted
uh in the 1980s,
1985, I believe it was, convicted of
spying for Israel and sentenced to life
in prison. 30 years, um it was the
minimum that he had to do. He served the
30 years. And I should add,
all the years that I was at the CIA,
every single time an Israeli prime
minister would come to meet with the
president, they would ask us to bomb
Iran and to release Pard. And every
single time whoever happened to be
president said no. Pard was finally
released what, 10 years ago now.
>> That's right. He was immediately granted
Israeli citizenship,
flown back to Israel on an Israeli
military plane,
>> greeted as a hero.
>> Greeted as a hero by Benjamin Netanyahu
at the airport, and instantly bestowed
with Israeli citizenship. Now he has the
balls, the unmititigated gall to run for
the Knesset in the next election as an
independent but associated with the
extreme rightwing of Israeli politics.
>> He wants to annex the occupied
territories completely.
>> Correct. Now, we already know, all of us
know that Mike Huckabe is so far to the
right that he's actually fallen off the
edge.
>> [clears throat]
>> He's an evangelical lunatic. He has no
business being in any governmental
position, but he was in an early
endorser of Donald Trump. And because
he's an evangelical and wants all the
Jews to return to Israel so that Jesus
can come back and the rapture can
happen, which never appears anywhere in
the Bible, by the way.
>> True.
>> Um,
>> and doesn't seem like a good deal for
the Jews, by the way.
>> Yeah, it doesn't. No, cuz it's the end
of the world. Exactly.
>> Yeah. They're just they're just the
lynch pin. It's like they're they're the
red shirts in this Star Trek episode.
>> This clown has got to go. Uh he won't
say and I should add they kept the pard
meeting off the uh embassy's calendar.
So only now are people finding out about
it and only because somebody called the
New York Times and told them. And then
the New York Times was able to confirm
it with two other people inside the
embassy. They interviewed Pard and he
said, "Yeah, I met with Huckabe. I'm not
going to tell you what we talked about.
Huckabe has to resign
today."
>> So So is I I want to be really clear
here. So, um, he should resign because
of the breach of protocol. He should
resign because of the cowtowing to a
traitor. He should like all of the above
more.
>> Yes.
>> I I I Yes to all of those. Yes. Yes. And
another thing too, the Post and the
Times are reporting today, and I think
this is quite important, that the White
House had no idea that this meeting took
place and that they're apoplelectic that
it took place. When, listen, I I've
worked in embassies for half my adult
life. When an ambassador is meeting with
somebody who is controversial,
>> they have to they have to cable the
secretary of state to ask permission.
>> Huckabe did not he did not do that.
>> What was Huckabe thinking? Why did Why
did he Why did he think I mean Donald
Trump does not strike anyone as the kind
of person that you do this to? Um, you
know, I mean, you wouldn't like it if
you were president. I wouldn't like it
either. Is he gonna survive this?
>> You know what? I think he will survive
it only because Donald Trump seems to
like the guy, but no other ambassador.
>> Also, he must worry about looking weak,
too, right? So, if he it'll it'll be
kind of a tacit admission if he fires
Huckabe that like Huckabe pulled the
wool over his eyes. Unless unless Trump
calls him and says, "Mike, you gotta
resign.
This is unacceptable."
And again, the both the Post and the
Times report that Huckabe, I'm sorry,
they report that Pard called Trump a
madman who has literally sold us down
the drain for Saudi gold.
>> You know, takes one man madman to no
one. I mean, Jonathan Pard, I mean, I
remember that very, very vividly. I
mean, you know, anyone who's old enough,
let's say over 50, remembers that very
well. And
>> I mean, he he really I mean, he probably
made the strongest case against dual
citizenship of of any human being I've
ever and and just so people remember,
I'm going to turn this light off real
quick. Just so people remember what it
was that Pard did. Pard sold top secret
military cables and NSA intercepts to
the Israelis. Sold it right for money.
>> The Israelis then traded that top secret
information to the Soviet Union in
exchange for Soviet Jews being allowed
to settle in Israel.
>> Pard did it for the money.
>> He was a traitor for money.
This was not um you know like uh this
was not a Kim Philby situation.
>> Absolutely not. [snorts]
>> Um okay. I mean look I I I think it's
disgusting too. Um I I hope the
president does the right thing. Uh I
have doubts to say the least. Um okay.
Um we have some questions. Let's get to
them. Fo thanks for the dollar. Um, what
do you make of the military Egyptian
planes following Erica Kirk as reported
by Candace?
>> Um, you know, I I checked that out. I
don't I don't think it ever happened.
Candace is literally the only person on
earth who's reporting this.
>> It's picked up by the Times of India and
the Hindustan Times and it's got a life
of its own around, you know, social
media, but I just don't think this has
ever this ever happened.
Uh yeah, I I that was my take as well.
Uh wouldn't be the first time that her
quote unquote reporting is uh less than
than waterproof. Um Three Birds, One
Stone on Rumble asks, "Maybe we should
start the show, although a little late
with that for that, with how the
Israelis killed more than 100
Palestinians last night and improvised
explosive exploded 124 buildings in Gaza
in a single day. What a ceasefire
they're keeping."
>> Yeah,
>> that's a very I'm glad I'm glad that you
brought that up. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, it's it's absolutely
disgusting. I mean, here's the thing,
right? Like, you pointed this out months
ago that the Israelis have a
long-standing practice of blowing up
every ceasefire that they ever agreed
to.
>> They got kic they got dragged into this
one kicking and screaming by President
Trump. Yes.
>> Um and uh and obviously they're trying
to screw it up every way that they
possibly can.
>> Trump is kind of in a really difficult
position, right? Because [clears throat]
if he if he calls up Netanyahu and yells
at him about this, then, you know, he
risks BB saying, "Okay, fine. [__] you.
Back to war." Um and and and then which
is exactly what what Netanyahu wants. Um
for a variety of reasons that we've
discussed here a billion times. Yeah. Um
uh the but if he doesn't do it, he comes
off as a puss,
>> which is not good either. That's right.
>> I don't know. I don't know what I would
do in this situation. Um I think I think
I would be starting to look at
threatening them with cutting off aid. I
mean that's always been where
>> that's what George HW Bush did. And you
have to be serious about it.
>> It's the only thing that gets their
attention, right?
>> That's it. That's it. And he didn't even
cut off aid. uh George HW Bush um
temporarily suspended loan guarantees
for new Israeli settlements in the West
Bank. [clears throat]
>> That's Yeah, that doesn't seem like such
a a big deal. Well, okay. Fo, thanks for
the extra dollar. Um has the CIA ever
assassinated their own agents or
officers like they're some kind of
cartel or prison gang?
Uh,
not that's ever been reported.
Um,
I don't know. You know, pre-1975 was the
bad old days. It I I I honestly can't
say no, but I don't know of any such
incidents.
>> Yeah, I don't remember reading any
allegations to that effect. It It seems
Wouldn't you say that seems a little bit
I think it's unlikely. Yeah, I I would
call it unlikely. Yeah,
>> John, this is from Ali Y3T. John, you
mentioned on Julian Dory, your first
boss who wrote books on history of
political relations of countries, but I
couldn't find his name. Maybe I missed
it. Could you let us know his name?
>> Yep. That was uh Bruce Ryell. Bruce was
one of the one of the best bosses I ever
had. and um and in his retirement he's
been absolutely prolific
uh in um
in uh his his uh book production. It's
incredible.
>> Another dollar from Fuso Fuso is that
keeps bringing bringing the dropping the
George Washingtons. Uh if you were or
Saka Joas depending uh if you were to be
a corrupt spy would you rather be
recruited by a hot Chinese spy or a hot
Russian spy?
Oh jeez. Oh man, what a totally loaded
question.
>> I'd have to say Russian for me.
>> Yeah, I'd have to go with the Russian
>> just because, you know,
isn't Pard also ethnically Jewish? For
sure.
>> 100%.
>> Yeah. Yeah. No, no doubt. He even he
I'll tell you what I I served in prison
with a with a mob guy named um well I
won't say it was I don't want to I don't
want to embarrass him but anyway good
guy from the uh from Philadelphia and he
was at the penitentiary in Butner with
uh with Pard and he said Pard was such a
little mouse he said everybody just
wanted to beat the daylights out of him
so they kept him for the most part in
the medical unit just for his own
protection.
>> Now he looks like Dave Letterman with a
post beard like like a like a [__]
wild man living like hill.
>> Yeah, he looks like a crazy person.
>> He didn't used to look like that at all.
Uh you know, he used to look like
Williamsburg man. Um
okay, Nicholas Franco asks, "Why do we
think the majority of Jews coming from
the Soviet Union are so right-wing?"
I don't know if that's necessarily true,
but I mean, you know, look, the thing is
my take is always that refugees tend to
be the uh you know, they they tend to
leave their home country because they're
opposed to the ideology of their home
country, which is like the anti-Castro
Cubans and so on. So, you know, the
Soviet Union was a socialist country.
So, you know, if you didn't love
socialism, you know, you're you left,
right? I mean, that's what do you think?
>> Yeah, I think that's right. Although it
is my understanding that Ukrainian Jews
who have left Ukraine to move to Israel
are exceedingly right-wing. Um I've I've
even spoken to Israeli journalists who
have told me that there are so many
right-wing Ukrainian Jews that have
moved there just over the last 20 or 25
years that it's pushed the entire
electorate to the right.
>> Crazy.
>> Yeah. I mean that's super interesting. I
mean that is a country that has a lot of
uh you know immigration uh in and that
country and and their demographics
change really radically in a relatively
short amount of time as a result. I mean
we don't have that level of immigration
in this country. Our our demographics we
sh we shift slowly.
>> Yeah, we do. We shift slowly and a
country of only 9 million people can
shift very quickly when you have these
huge influxes.
>> Yeah. 100,000 is a lot of people for in
a country of 9 million people.
>> That's right.
>> Um a quadruple JXYZ. Do you think do we
think the un unveiled corruption in
Ukraine unveiled [laughter] my ass? It's
like it's always been in open uh in
plain sight will influence the Western
support in any ways. It's a great
question though. Um you we're talking
about of course the recent scandal um of
the people surrounding Zalinski. Yeah.
uh in this um you know energy bribery uh
kind of thing which kind of has echoes
of the Hunter Biden Berisma [__] Um you
know I don't what what do you think
John? I I I I don't think that the US is
going to back away from Ukraine. I mean
you know corruption goes with the
territory over there. It does.
>> And and it's like it's it's not unusual.
And it's doesn't it remind you a little
bit of Hamid Carzi where it's like
basically like everyone around you is
corrupt as [__]
>> but no one can prove that you personally
took money. This isn't like Eric Adams
who is personally corrupt and was had
credible charges filed against him. I
mean, nobody really I mean, Zilinski
suddenly is rich and has this place in,
you know, on Lake Ko, but he's maybe he
was just a he has a lot of good a lot of
good residuals from his acting career or
I mean, we can't prove it, right? But
like Hamid Carzai, you certainly could
never prove that he personally was
lining his pockets. This is kind of like
President Harding or something like
that.
I I I think that's a good way to uh to
say it and and President Harding
[laughter] is probably the right uh the
right comparison to make. Yeah, I agree
with that. I agree with that. But you
know what's painful too, Ted, is that
nobody seems to really care no
>> when leaders are corrupt now.
>> Well, nobody cares about their whether
we're talking about domestic or foreign
affairs. Nobody cares when their own
side is called out. I mean, basically,
there's never a thing where it's like,
"Oh, I supported this candidate or this
party, but now I've learned new
information that that they're a turd, so
therefore I no longer support them
anymore." That doesn't happen anymore.
You're just like, now you just make
excuses or you just brush it off or you
do what aboutism or you know, but you
don't change your mind. You don't back
away. Like literally nothing can make
you do that. Like you could if your
person if your guy your candidate turns
out to be a pedophile you're like ah
whatever you know the other side's worse
no matter what it is.
>> I I feel like that's a change. I don't
think that was true. I think about you
know when I was a little kid you were a
little kid during Watergate. Nixon won
by a landslide in 1972. By 1974, you
couldn't find anyone who admitted that
they voted for.
>> You know what, George George McGovern
told me something one time that was so
funny. He said that that in 1972
he [snorts] got 39% of the national
vote, but
>> he only got South Dakota and the
District of Columbia.
>> No, he lost South Dakota. He got
Massachusetts.
>> Okay. My god.
>> And the District of Columbia.
Ridiculous. Then in 1974, two years
later, 65% of Americans told pollsters
that they voted for McGovern. [laughter]
>> That is that is that is the total uh you
know, victory has a thousand fathers and
defeat as an orphan. It really is true.
>> It is true.
>> Um
>> yes, it is.
>> Rebellious rainbow unicorn. Is the CIA
more out of control now compared to
pre995, John? pre195 absolutely yes. No,
no question. Pre-1975
I think that um that it's comparable.
Pre-1975
the CIA was just going around the world
doing anything it pleased. They were
killing world leaders. They were
overthrowing governments. Half the time
they weren't even bothering to inform
the president what they were doing. And
>> doping kids with LSD.
>> Doping kids. Doping their own employees
with LSD. Yeah. and um they they had
seriously cleaned up their act by 1995.
I talk often about the the so-called
cull that uh Bill Clinton initiated in
1993 where he ordered the CIA to fire
every recruited source who had a human
rights problem in his past and fully
onethird of the CIA sources were were
fired. Um,
those days are gone and they're never
coming back.
>> So, can you explain like why do you
think why do you think the CIA in other
words, how did the CIA get so out of
like what causes it? What caused it to
happen before 75? I know the church
committee came in afterwards and there
were all the scandals because of Philip
Agi and all that, but like when the CIA
is more under control,
>> what's the difference between that and a
and a time like now when they're out of
control? Like what's the, you know, is
it leadership? Like what is it?
>> Um, it is the nature of the CIA. It's
the the the collective mindset of the
CIA to push the envelope as far as you
can push until somebody in the White
House pushes back or somebody on Capitol
Hill pushes back. It's they
>> it's the culture.
>> It's the culture. They they called it um
um kingdom building.
Kingdom building is what they called it
when I was there. Everybody in a
position of authority at the CIA wants
to build his or her own kingdom. And so
you just keep pushing the the boundaries
of legality until somebody pushes back
and the next thing you know they're
doing anything they damn well please.
There's almost zero congressional
oversight and at the White House there
they just throw up their hands and say
well what can we do? There's nothing we
can do.
>> And these days so so it's the lack of uh
interest in reigning them in coming from
the White House. You would say
>> I would and and I would say the
inability to rein them in on the part of
the congressional oversight committees.
>> Why are they unable to?
>> Because there are about um 40 employees
of the Senate Intelligence Committee and
about 60 employees of the House
Intelligence Committee and 40,000
employees at the CIA.
>> That's a good answer.
>> And you just can't you can't handle it.
Um, okay. Uh, Peruse, a JFK related
question. Have you from Peru? Have you
met or worked with David Talbet
>> and and what do you think about his
work? My impression is that he's not in
good health nowadays. I'm sorry to hear
that about David. Poor
>> David. You know him? [clears throat]
>> Yeah. He David wrote the uh the forward
for my third book. He's a he's a lovely
guy and one of the most highly respected
contemporary historians that's out
there. He had a debilitating serious
stroke. his second stroke a few months
ago and um the last I heard was unable
to to care for himself, unable to speak
and certainly unable to write. The poor
guy.
>> He was the editor of Salon.
>> Yeah, he was.
>> And uh I I so my only interaction was
trying to get him to run my cartoons. He
ran the cartoons of four of my
colleagues who were very similar to the
kind of work that I did. So I thought I
kind of belonged naturally in that
orbit. It's the kind of and yet and you
know he he was nice but he obviously
it's one of those things where he he
obviously didn't like my work and just
didn't want to say so and uh and he
never ran it ever and uh you know it was
it was always fr a source of frustration
to me but you know he's allowed to not
like my work um you know that was my
interaction with him he was always
polite he was always polite but albeit a
little weasly about it um editors USX X
A-Rod 21. Thanks for the $2. Have you
seen the ide
Polish train tracks with C4 explosives?
Was Poland right to worry about Putin
and his ambitions? Or is this mind games
Putin is playing? Is there a real issue?
In other words, is there a real danger
of Russia invading Poland here?
>> Yeah. Um, yes, the polls have reason to
be uh to be worried. Really? Yeah, I do.
I I do believe that. Listen, the
Russians the Russians are just like
every other country, just like every
other superpower or regional superpower.
Um they're going to they're going to
carry out um uh operations against the
countries that they believe are threats
to them. And sometimes those operations
are are large scale and sometimes
they're small scale. But sabotage is
just a normal a normal thing.
>> I mean it's almost I mean it's not
really I mean it's almost an act of war,
right? I mean going into a sovereign
state and
country transportation infrastructure.
>> Absolutely right.
>> But listen, even if they got caught,
nobody's going to go to war over some
train tracks.
>> I got to but I do I think I just I disag
would invade Poland.
>> No. No. I don't think absolutely not
because to invade Poland is to invade
NATO and then it's going to require a
massive response. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Um, Destined for Nothing says,
"John, I saw a job posting yesterday now
removed for a director of identity
intelligence at Health and Human
Services." Oh, sorry. Uhuh. HHS. Yeah,
Health and Human Services. Can you shed
some light on what that could mean? A
director of identity intelligence.
>> The word identity throws me. I I
honestly don't know what that could
mean. It's It's not unusual for almost
every federal department to have an
intelligence office. Uh, for example,
there's a there's a CIA representative
from the analytic side, from the
director of intelligence at Treasury, at
commerce, at energy, they're all over
the place. Um, just because there is
intelligence that comes in every day
that needs to be shared with the
leaderships of those departments, right?
Maybe you pick up something about
threats to air travel or about some germ
that's been developed somewhere or you
stole the Japanese, you know, trade
negotiation talking points and you need
to share them or whatever. Uh, but
identity intelligence,
it it doesn't have a meaning for me. I'm
not sure what that is.
>> I mean, all I can think of is HHS has
clients. Maybe they want to know if
they're US US citizens or they they want
to know who they are,
>> but that would that would normally fall
it's possible, but that would normally
fall under the Office of Security.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, yeah, I have no I have no
clue here. Um
>> Oh, rebellious rainbow. Rebellious. And
see, I remember I remembered just to say
rebellious instead of the whole
rebellious rainbow unicorn.
>> [laughter]
>> says identity access is cyber security.
That would make sense.
>> Thank you for that.
>> Uh Nicholas Franco, do you see do we see
Trump getting the rare earth medals from
Ukraine as per that deal? It seems to me
that Putin is getting all of them. Well,
Putin has occupies the territory where
they are and that territory is never
going back to Ukraine ever.
>> No sir. So
>> it is not. By the way, thank you so much
RC2020. Longtime listener and viewer is
now a monthly supporter of GP program.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Much appreciate it.
>> Fuso, here's a buck. John, this is your
question. What would it take to actually
reform or dismantle the CIA?
>> Can I get away with saying stay tuned to
this uh channel?
>> Yes, you you you can. And I know why.
Um, yes.
>> I'm I'm hoping to have kind of a big
announcement in the next two weeks.
>> Yeah, that'll be cool. Maybe two. Maybe
two announcements. Maybe.
>> May maybe two announcements.
>> All right. Um, Kahunk Kapun T589. Do we
think that Israel has crossed the point
of no return in regards to how the world
sees Israelis or does it take time and
people will forget that Israel committed
genocide? I think 100% there's no going
back. I mean, I think it's so radical at
this point. Um, you know, they've fallen
off the cliff in international opinion
polling and domestic opinion polling and
most importantly with young people,
which means that these are opinions that
are baked into the generations that are
going to be moving forward over the next
few decades. Um, I don't see even if
Israel were to if ne were to say we were
wrong, we apologize. We want to help
create a Palestinian state. I mean, you
know, none of these things are going to
happen. But even if they did that, I
think it's it's not going to be
forgiven. I think it went on for so
long. It was so extreme and now it's
being so reported. It's baked in. I
don't see that being I think it's I
think Israel's kind of dead to a
significant percentage of the
population. What do you think?
>> With the exception of Arab countries who
do as they're told and don't give
don't give
a [__] about the Palestinians. Yeah, the
Israelis are not going to expand their
their list of uh you know global
countries that uh that they can rely on
for support. I I personally believe the
Israelis are beyond the point of no
return. I really do. too. Uh there and I
don't think I mean and just to be clear
the Arab countries you're talking about,
John, I don't want to put words in your
mouth ever, but we're talking about the
governments of those countries, not the
citizens of those.
>> That's right. That is exactly right.
Glad you said that. [snorts]
>> Okay. So, um let's talk about while
we're while we're talking all things
CIA, let's talk about the JFK
assassination, which uh took place 62
years ago um this coming Saturday,
November 22nd. Um, former CIA historian
Tom Percy uh says that he basically was
doing research in a CIA safe room back
in 2009 while looking researching Latin
American policy in the CIA and he came
across a 50-page IG inspector general's
report from 1978
in which this was a period during under
the Carter administration during the
Church Committee when the CIA was really
on the hot seat for the abuses in Latin
America. And uh they basically were
laughing about the memo, laughing and
bragging about uh fooling Congress about
what Lee Harvey Oswald was up to in
Mexico City before he killed JFK. Um the
uh the det shows basically it's this is
kind of considered a a blueprint for how
you can lie to Congress uh as a
government agency spec and uh and
basically there were sanitized in other
words uh expuned duplicates of files
sent to the House Select Committee Chief
Counsel. They got rid of all the key
evidence
>> and they insulted him. They they
insulted him by calling him incurious.
Well, it sounds like they weren't wrong.
It sounds like he didn't he he sort of
did a give everything a quick over, you
know, 20 30 minute glance and then back
to scotch on the rocks, right? Um and um
yeah, and that's probably true, but
although it is it's always kind of funny
to me when someone uh engages in
pernitious activity like this and then
laughs at their victims for being
stupid. Um
>> yes,
>> which I guess is what happened here. Um,
John, can you talk a little bit about
this? I mean, you know, first of all,
this sounds credible to me. Um, what was
Lee Harvey Oswald up to in Mexico City
before
the November 22nd?
>> He he was there to meet at the Soviet
embassy, which turned him away, and at
the Chinese embassy, which also turned
him away. Uh we only learned recently
that that the CIA was surveilling him in
Mexico City in this most recent trunch
of uh of documents. Uh but the CIA
denied and denied and denied that they
had any knowledge of Oswald being in
Mexico City. That was a lie. And another
lie is, and we just learned this in the
latest trunch, the other lie was that um
that the CIA had no contact with Oswald.
And not only did they have contact with
Oswald, but James Angleton, the deputy
director for counter intelligence,
ordered that the CIA recruit Oswald,
even if Oswald didn't realize he had
been recruited.
So, you know,
>> what would that look like?
>> Oh, you can you can do it as a false
flag. You can do it pretending to be
Russian, for example, or you can say
you're a businessman looking to hire a
consultant. Uh, you can do you can tell
any kind of lie you want just to set the
person's mind at ease.
>> Why was the CIA um why did they feel a
need to not reveal that? What would be
what would have been exposed by them
just saying, "Yeah, you know, we were
surveilling him and here's what we
knew."
Yeah, that's that's just inexplicable,
Ted.
The the CIA would have been so much
better off, the country would have been
so much better off just being honest
from the beginning. Just
>> or did they think it would raise
additional questions?
>> I think they probably did, but but you
and I, we just said this a couple of
days ago, didn't we? That it the cover
up is always worse than the crime.
And so, yeah,
>> but they just didn't want to It sounds
to me like they just didn't want to be
>> Well, you know, basically they didn't
want to be second-guessed. Like, didn't
you know he was g he was plotting to
kill the president? If if so, why didn't
you, you know, or did you know and did
you let it happen? Did you continue to
surveil him when he came to Dallas?
Right. I mean, they just didn't they
just did they couldn't they just didn't
want to be bothered. It sounds like
>> I think that's exactly what it was. and
and just gloating that the that the
chief investigator was incurious. That
that leads me to believe that it was an
issue of gloating.
>> That's that's uh and then um thanks for
the uh $299 Australian dollars from
Tabby Jay. Unfortunately, Tabby, we have
already answered your question. Why has
Huckabe met with uh Jonathan Pard in
Jerusalem? Um we talked about that
earlier in the show. Um, but uh, thanks
for the thanks for the 299. Just hit
rewind. Um,
>> hey, um,
uh, MW Knox 186 has a good practical
question. Did I ever recruit anyone
without identifying myself as a CIA
employee?
>> That is a good question.
>> The answer is yes. Um, there was
somebody I was working on who I knew had
an irrational fear of the CIA. And so I
said that I represented a consortium of
businessmen
and they were interested in this very
specific information and they were
willing to pay handsomely for it. So I
had headquarters draw up what looked
like a really official legal contract
and I offered the guy the contract. It
was a consulting contract. And so he
signed it and uh I gave him five grand a
month in cash in hotel rooms and he gave
me the the classified information and uh
everybody lived happily ever after.
>> That's a funny That is a funny story. Um
if you so thanks for the additional
dollar. What do you know uh John I
assume about the story of the Falcon and
the Snowman? Oh yeah,
>> movie. I The Sean Penn movie. I don't
know.
>> Oh, The Falcon and the Snowman. The
>> movie.
>> Oh, it was a great movie. It was a great
book. Uh, but this is something that
from the day that you're hired at the
CIA, they they drill into you. So, every
new CIA employee knows the story of the
Falcon and the snowman. So, uh, two best
friends, two high school best friends
who grad graduated from, uh, from high
school. One went on to go to college.
One went on to be a drug addict and a
drug dealer. And the one that went to
college uh got a job with a with a CIA
contractor.
And so
he had access, of course, to classified
information. the drug addict friend
ended up going down to Mexico to Mexico
City and approaching the Soviet embassy
and saying, "Hey, I've got a buddy who
um who works uh for the CIA and uh if
you give me money, I'll get the uh the
information that you want from my
friend." And then he used that money to
buy more drugs.
And it was all fine and good until they
got caught. And uh one cooperated or or
both cooperated. Actually, I'm going to
Google it now because I can't remember
if it was one or both that cooperated,
but uh they both ended up with long
prison sentences.
I'm gonna look it up right now.
>> While you're hearing that Oh, go ahead.
Go ahead. Yeah, it it was uh Christopher
Boyce who was played by Timothy Hutton.
>> Mhm.
>> Uh his dad got him a job at the CIA and
uh
>> disgusting.
>> Yeah. His his friend finally admitted,
"Hey, I've been all that all the
questions that I ask you, I uh I've been
uh telling the Soviet embassy in Mexico
City." He suggested that they run off to
Costa Rica where he had secretly bought
a house. instead. Um, Boyce, um, Boyce
turned himself in.
>> Yeah. The reason they called him the
falcon and the snowman is the Timothy
Hutton character raised falcons.
>> And, um, the snowman was
self-explanatory.
>> A cokehead. Yeah. [laughter]
>> Right. Uh, Sean Pat 6882. Is the fear of
the CIA ever irrational? I'd say no.
>> No.
>> Fear of government is never rational.
Um, I love this question. Roie Bang
Bang, what do we think about this new
commercial that the Democrats put out
telling American soldiers that they
don't have to follow unlawful orders?
>> I saw this last
>> dangerous if I say so myself, he says or
she says,
>> you know, the Democrats have this
obsession that Donald Trump is going to,
you know, try to seize power and refuse
to leave the White House at the end of
his term. Um, and Trump loves trolling
them on [clears throat] issues like
this. Yeah.
>> So, the Democrats last week,
>> the Democrats have some cause to be
concerned about [laughter] that. In
fairness,
>> maybe just a little. Um, I think Trump's
just enjoying himself watching the the
Democrats, you know, lose their minds
over this. So several dem more than
several half a dozen Democratic leaders
last week came out with this nicely
produced advertisement
urging members of the military to defy
illegal orders unlawful orders that you
know if Trump says he's not leaving he's
going to declare himself dictator
whatever
>> that
>> I'm wondering what that all I took that
also as as having to do with uh you know
the the the ICE actions on the streets
and the National Guard uh being sent to
various American cities like they're in
Charlotte.
>> Oh, that would be more immediate. I
didn't see it that way. That would be a
little bit scarier.
>> I mean, so it's it's so like impossible,
right? like like I'm I've never
understood how members of the military
reconcile this innate contradiction
which you and I have talked about before
>> between being told that you have to
follow orders unquestioningly from your
commanding officer [clears throat] and
at the same time you shouldn't and in
fact you're legally prohibited from
following unlawful orders. Those two
directives seem to me like they're going
to come into conflict and it's
impossible for a service person to to
know what to do in a in a mai type
situation. Um you know I mean you know
what you know what's morally right.
>> Yeah.
>> But but I mean what are you really truly
I feel like it's an impossible
situation.
>> I wouldn't want to be in a situation
like this. It's like it's like at the
very end of his first term when Trump
walked out into that demonstration uh in
front of St. John's um uh church across
the street from the White House and
asked the chairman of the Joint Chiefs
of Staff, "Well, why don't you just
shoot them?"
>> And he's like, "Serious? I I have to
explain to you why we can't just go out
and shoot unarmed civilians in the
streets in front of the White House."
>> Insane. Uh so I mean, I don't know. Is
it dangerous? I mean, is it dangerous to
say to to have a political party say you
don't ha, you know, hey, you don't have
to necessarily follow the orders that
you get when you're [clears throat]
in the armed services.
>> I mean, I mean, it's a statement of
fact. You don't necessarily,
>> right? It could be dangerous. Yes. And I
think the Democrats are jumping the gun
on this.
>> I really do. I mean, it does seem like
probably um you know, I wish that they
frankly I wish that they'd had less
balls here and more balls in the
showdown over the shutdown because you
know that one where they didn't want to
they were afraid of [__] the airline
lobby. That's what this was about. Let
me read an ad, John. Looking for smarter
ways to browse and enjoy your favorite
content without ads? Get the Perplexity
Pro bundle with Rumble Premium for just
$19.99 a month while you sign up when
you sign up before December 31st.
Normally, it's a $29.99 value. With
Rumble Premium, you'll get an ad-free
viewing experience across all your
devices, and access to exclusive premium
content, no interruptions, just the
videos and streams you love anytime,
anywhere. Plus, Perplex Perplexity Pro
boosts your productivity with unlimited
research, unlimited uploads, exclusive
member perks, and access to the latest
and most advanced AI models for faster,
smarter answers every day. Save over 30%
on this powerful bundle. Head to
rumble.com/premium
before December 31st to sign up and
unlock your premium experience. And um
thank you. By the way, we are on the
front page of of of Rumble right now,
even as we speak. So,
>> hey, great.
>> That's that's fun and exciting. Um and
thank you very much for the $10 donation
from V Village Idiot TV. Much
appreciated.
>> That's wonderful. Thank you.
Um, okay. So, let's uh shall we talk
about um we have good timing here today.
Uh sometimes we run out of time, but it
seem Okay. So, Donald Trump and uh Zoron
Mdani, the mayor elect of New York City,
who takes office in about six weeks, um
are going to meet at the White House in
the Oval Office tomorrow.
>> Ted, I thought you were joking when you
sent this to me. I have to [laughter]
look it up.
>> No, it's true. Apparently, this is a
tradition for the new mayor of New York
City. Um, from what we've heard, Mumdani
has a um requested the meeting T.
Mumdani. Um, Trump agreed. All right.
So, I have many questions. All right.
So, there's the meta question of what
does it say? I mean, how many times do
the American people have to sit through
an election where two side the two
adversaries repeatedly say how, you
know, the other, you know, like John
Kiryaku is the devil himself. He's evil.
He hangs out with Satan. He's going to
destroy America. And then Ted R is scum.
He's a horrible communist. He's going
to, you know, send everyone to goologs.
And then it's like the election's over.
It's like maybe John's not so bad. Ted's
okay. And then like, oh, I love you.
Let's work together for the I mean, I
know that's like the tradition. And I it
works. It worked historically, but I
just feel like in a time of social media
and everything. It's hard going forward
to take anything that any politician
ever says seriously because you know
that they're likely going to end up in
this place, right? like like the guy I
can't pronounce his name. Uh the the the
Grastidis dude.
>> Oh, John Katy.
>> HE'S LIKE, "OH, I want the best now for
for Mandani. I'm not going anywhere."
St. Petersburg. Yeah. He's going to move
to St. Petersburg because he can never
live in a socialist city. And now he's
like, "Ah, Manny's not so bad."
>> Right. I mean, so like, okay, so first
of all, is it going to be maybe maybe
not a lovein, but will it be a like in
tomorrow and uh or will it be sort of
like, you know, Vance Vance versus
Zilinski? I mean, what's it what's going
to happen?
Yeah, I I think it is going to be a like
in um by most accounts, unless your name
is uh Wimir Zalinski, uh Trump treats
people with respect when they when they
visit him in the White House. And um and
I think that they're going to
make public statements in the end about
areas in which they can cooperate. I
think Mom Donnie is going to say, "Look,
we're not trying to take over the
grocery stores. for I I appointed the
same police commissioner that that Mayor
Adams appointed. She's staying on in the
job. I I think
>> by the way, she's from a really rich
family, too.
>> Oh, I didn't know that.
>> Oh, yeah. No, she's from the the famous
Tishes, like
>> Oh, for heaven's sake.
>> She's one of
>> like Lawrence Tish. Oh, boy. Oh, boy.
Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> All right.
>> I don't know why she'd want to be the
head of the NYPD, but
>> yeah, right. Why?
>> Just sit home and count your money.
[snorts] But I I think that's what we're
we're going to see. I think this is
going to be a liken. They'll agree to
disagree like you know gentlemen. And um
Mani is no threat to Trump and Trump
really can't do much to hurt Mumani
especially when Mumani is surrounding
himself with with people from the Adams
uh administration.
>> Yeah, he is. And also I mean Mandani's
been very canny about uh making nice
with Governor Hokll which is right the
most important connection
>> that is possibly have. I mean you know
Andrew Cuomo never got along with uh uh
Mayor Delasio.
>> Um
>> that was a problem for Delasio.
>> Although these days Delasio is looking
good. Uh [laughter]
he really is.
>> He's got a new girlfriend. He's got a TV
gig. Yeah. Things are good for him.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And not to mention his
mayoralty. Um it turns out to have been
>> Adams. Oh my god.
>> Yeah. I mean I just heard a story just
for example. This is a very local New
York City story, but um he had uh when
he became mayor, he quietly and never
bragged about this ordered the NYPT NYPD
to completely dig into all the backlog
of rape kits and process them all and
get completely caught up. And now the
Adams administration immediately fell
behind. and uh and you know basically
we're right back where we started. But
that was an example of something Delasio
took seriously and uh and cared about.
>> You know, my my best friend uh lives in
New York all of his life on the Lower
East Side. um his uh one and only child,
his daughter just graduated from high
school. But when she was a freshman
uh 3 years ago, four years ago, whatever
it is, she was walking home from school
like she did every day, walking up First
Avenue, and a homeless guy walked up to
her and punched her in the face as hard
as he could. Almost knocked her out and
then just walked away. And when my
friend called the cops, the cops are
like, "What do you want us to do about
it? This kind of thing happens."
>> That happened to me.
>> I was I was walking out of the Chamber
Street subway station years ago. And uh
and a homeless guy coming down the
stairs just casually slugged me in the
face, broke my glasses. I'm lucky the
glass didn't go into my eyes. And it was
just like he just left. And it's the
same sort of I didn't even bother to go
to the cops because it's true. What What
do you want them to do? Yeah.
>> I mean, even if they caught the [__]
uh, you know, I mean, he's not going to
stay he's they're not going to keep him
in prison. I mean, you know, that's it.
He's going to be out on the street 5
seconds later.
>> The point I wanted to make was that at
least under uh Adams,
uh, there was no real move to make the
streets any safer. There are these
catastrophes happening in subway
stations, people being beaten, raped,
mugged, shoved in front of trains. It
happens practically every week or two.
>> And uh and this guy was a police
captain.
>> Yeah. I thought he was supposed to be
the law and order candidate. Instead, he
was just a bozo.
Um yeah. By the way, speaking of which,
remember that really crazy story um uh
in New York in uh I think this happened
in Cody Island at the end of the line
and in Brooklyn where a lady was um set
on fire, a homeless lady was set on fire
by some degenerate.
>> Well, the a similar event just happened
yesterday in Chicago um where a woman uh
was set on I don't know if it was a
woman or a man, the victim, someone was
set on fire um and the suspect was
apprehended. I was wondering, you know,
we're this wasn't a mean, but what do
you think about the fact that the
Chicago police have decided to charge
him with uh with terrorism? The uh the
the the arsonist.
Oh, God. We we've talked about this in
the past. Terrorism
is
inflicting
terror [snorts] on a population for a
political purpose.
>> Yeah. So, this is not terrorism.
>> No, it's not. Let's go through some
comments. Um, Bill 2082, ISIS is
literally not evil. They are literally
not doing evil. It is literally not evil
to enforce immigration laws. Democrats
are evil for committing sedition and
treason with that video. I I I like I
appreciate the comment. Um, and here's
the thing. I agree 100% that um you know
a country has the duty and the and the
right to enforce its laws and illegal
immigration is illegal. But the thing is
how you enforce the law matters. Like if
a cop stop, you know, stops you for
speeding, he can't just shoot you. Well,
he was enforcing the law. It's like,
okay, but he wasn't enforcing the law
the right way. I is not enforcing the
law the right way. They're ethnic
they're ethnic ethnically profiling.
They're grabbing and we know they're
ethnically profiling because they're
grabbing people who are US citizens
including native days.
>> Native Americans who happen to have
brown skin.
>> Yeah.
>> Are are being arrested and detained in
one case deported to Mexico.
>> Yeah. So that's I mean and also there's
and also there's prosecutorial
discretion, right? Like obviously a cop
should pull, you know, if the speed
limit's 55, the cop should pull over the
dude going 95 before he pulls over the
guy going 58. And like this is again ICE
is not doing that. ICE is going they're
not going after like convicted rapists
who are illegal immigrants. They're
going after sort of anyone and everyone
and it seems almost like the lowhanging
fruit is people dropping their kids off
at school and stuff. I mean it's wrong.
Um question for both of us. Do we
consume media in your other languages
like music, movies, TV, etc.? I
absolutely do. Um, I watch French films
>> and I listen to French music 100%.
>> Listen, I I even have this app on my
phone called um called
is eronia,
Greek radio and television.
This this Netflix has like every channel
in Greece and you can watch movies and
concerts and soap operas and sports
events.
>> I watch it every single day. And then I
>> TV for France for for Greece.
>> Yeah. There's a there's a TV station in
Patras, Greece's third city on the west
coast that has its own app. I watch
Patras TV and then and then the church
of Greece has its own app, its own TV
station. So I just watch uh I I stopped
going to church I don't know a year ago.
So I just watch church on TV on Sunday
mornings.
>> I will I will I will want to ask you
about the not going to church. But let's
uh ask get try to get through some more
questions. Rasmataz request for you
John. Please recount one of your best
Alec Baldwin stories for us when time
permits. I haven't heard a single Alec
Baldwin story since the Sputnik Assange
days and then his film Rust. I have a I
have I have a Alec story too, but go
ahead.
>> Alec Baldwin and I hate each other
>> and hate each other to the point where
we can't be in the same room together.
And uh how did this the story
>> we met once a a friend of mine wanted to
write a play about my trial or the the
the case leading up to trial and he
wanted to do it off Broadway and
Alec was interested in playing me
>> and so we met for lunch one day in New
York.
>> Amazing.
>> And my friend my friend's an Academy
Award-winning writer, screenwriter. So,
>> John, you're kind of frozen here.
>> Book, etc., etc.
>> And Oh, shoot. Can you hear me at least?
>> Yes. Now, now you're good. Yeah, you
froze up for about 30 seconds.
>> Okay, thanks.
Oh, shoot. So,
so he asked me to tell him these
stories. I'm telling these stories. 30
minutes into it, Alex says, "I think
you're full of shit." Like that. And I
said, "Excuse me?"
>> Wow.
>> And he says, "I think you're full of
[__] I think you're just making all
this [__] up." And I said, "I've been
called a lot of things in my life, but
liar is not one of them." He goes, "Fuck
you." I said, "Fuck you, Baldwin." And I
I was so angry, I got up and I walked
out of the restaurant. And my friend is
like, "Guys, please, no, please. please.
So, I was so mad. I walked all the way
back to Penn Station. I got on the train
and I came home. So, about 6 months
later, I had this idea for a TV series.
I had written a pilot. And this I do
this as a hobby. I've I've written seven
of them in the last 14 years, and I've
actually sold all seven. One made it to
pilot. So, we we made this pitch at at
Fox, and Fox is like, "Nah, we're not
really interested. It's it's moderately,
you know, interesting, but it's not for
us. So, our next pitch meeting was at
AMC.
>> And before we went in, my buddy said,
you know, we can guarantee a sale to MSC
to AMC if we can attach an A-list star.
>> And I said, oh, please don't. I said,
please. [laughter] He says, he is he
he's an Academy Award winner. He's an
Emmy award winner. So, we called him. We
went to Soho House. They have breakout
rooms there. We called him and um my
friend said, "Uh, Alec, I'm I'm here
with Kiryaku." And um and Baldwin says,
"What's that [__] want?" And I said,
"Yeah, nice to talk to you, too, Alec."
And then uh he said, "Well, John's got
an idea for a show." And I told him the
idea for the show and he says,
"Actually, that is a pretty good idea.
Go ahead and attach me." So, we attached
him. We sold it to AMC the very next day
and um six weeks later I called my
attorney and I said, "I haven't heard
anything from AMC's business affairs
office. I have no idea if my deal's been
negotiated." He said, "You know, I
forgot all about that. Let me call over
there." He calls over to AMC and AMC
says, "Oh, we dropped that show." And my
attorney says, "Why?"
Cuz Alec Baldwin quit to take a deal
with HBO. So I called him back and I
said, "Fuck you, Baldwin. Don't ever
call me again." and I hung up. That was
the last time we spoke.
>> Yeah. I don't think it doesn't It sounds
like this relationship, this friendship
might be beyond redemption, John. Just
saying.
>> Yeah. No. And then and then when he when
he got arrested for shooting that uh
assistant director or whatever she was
on the on the movie Rust, my buddy
called and said, "Hey, you know, it
looks like Alec may be going to prison.
You might want to give him a ring and
just try to" And I said, "Fuck him. I
hope he rots in prison."
OMG. Uh, thanks for the five bucks, an
Angela Fala la. Thank you. Much
appreciated. Quick last question. Hype
show. Will Mundani really imprison BB if
he comes to New York or is that just
talk? Oh, I think it's I think it's
real.
>> I think it's real
>> and and it should be honestly.
>> Yes.
>> Yes, indeed.
>> Everyone, thanks so much for joining us.
This is the Deep Program Show with me,
Ted Roll and John Kuryaku. Uh, we are
here Monday through Friday at 9:00 a.m.
Eastern time, which means we will be
back tomorrow, December 1st. Friday at
9:00 a.m. We will see you then. Please
stay tuned for the TMI show with me and
Manila Chan coming right up after this.
Uh, much appreciate you. And, uh, oh,
also DMZ America podcast. Scott Sanders
and I will be interviewing editorial
cartoonist Steve Kelly uh, who's a
conservative. That's at 11:00 a.m.
Eastern time this morning. Bye, John.
See you tomorrow. Bye-bye everybody.
[music]